//Note : We have kept 15 questions for a safer side. The number of questions they answer in 1 min, will be considered.

export const questions = [
	//For 1st choice
	[
		{
			question: '1) Scurvy  is caused by the deficiency of Vitamin _____.',
			answer: 'Vitamin C'
		},
		{
			question: '2) Capital of Iran?',
			answer: 'Tehran'
		},
		{
			question: '3) Currency of Japan?',
			answer: 'Yen'
		},
		{
			question: '4) S.I. Unit of Luminous Intensity?',
			answer: 'Candella'
		},
		{
			question: '5) Author of the Book ‘How I taught my grandmother to read’ ?',
			answer: 'Sudha Murthy'
		},
		{
			question: '6) World Population Day is celebrated on?',
			answer: '11 July'
		},
		{
			question: '7) Bal Gangadhar Tilak started a Marathi Newspaper called?',
			answer: 'Kesari'
		},
		{
			question: '8) Number of strings in Violin?',
			answer: '4'
		},
		{
			question: '9) Full form of ILO?',
			answer: 'International Labour Organization'
		},
		{
			question: '10) Square of 0.4 is?',
			answer: '0.16'
		},
		{
			question: '11) Invader who carried Kohinoor from India?',
			answer: 'Nadir Shah'
		},
		{
			question: '12) Grammy awards are given for excellence in?',
			answer: 'Music'
		},
		{
			question:
				'13) Freedom fighter who gave the slogan ‘Inquilab Zindabad’ was?',
			answer: 'Bhagat Singh'
		},
		{
			question: '14) Anagram of EAT ?',
			answer: 'TEA/ATE'
		},

		{
			question: '15) Second largest flightless bird?',
			answer: 'Emu'
		}
	],
	//For 2nd choice
	[
		{
			question: '1) Founder of Anandwan?',
			answer: 'Baba Amte'
		},
		{
			question: '2) 3 Kilograms = _______ Decagrams?',
			answer: '300'
		},
		{
			question: '3) Doctor who specializes in skin care is called?',
			answer: 'Dermatologist'
		},
		{
			question: '4) A piece of fertile land in a desert is called?',
			answer: 'Oasis'
		},
		{
			question: '5) Author of the book ‘The Alchemist’?',
			answer: 'Paulo Coelho'
		},
		{
			question: '6) Place where India conducts its nuclear tests?',
			answer: 'Pokhran'
		},
		{
			question: '7) Winner of Rajiv Gandhi Khel Ratna Award 2019 is?',
			answer: 'Virat Kohli / Mirabai Chanu'
		},
		{
			question: '8) Full form of PETA is?',
			answer: 'People for Ethical Treatment of Animals'
		},
		{
			question: '9) International Yoga Day is celebrated on?',
			answer: '21st June'
		},
		{
			question: '10) The activist also known as ‘Loknayak’?',
			answer: 'Jayaprakash Narayan'
		},
		{
			question:
				'11) The line which intersects a circle in two distinct points is called?',
			answer: 'Secant'
		},
		{
			question: '12) The Everest of Maharashtra?',
			answer: 'Kalsubai Shikhar'
		},
		{
			question: '13) Currency of Canada?',
			answer: 'Dollar'
		},
		{
			question: '14) Place where Golconda Fort is situated in India?',
			answer: 'Hyderabad'
		},

		{
			question: '15) ‘Biopic’ is the combination of which 2 words?',
			answer: 'Biographical + Picture'
		}
	],
	//For 3rd choice
	[
		{
			question: '1) A person who studies Maps is?',
			answer: 'Cartographer'
		},
		{
			question: '2) S.I. Unit for Electric Charge is?',
			answer: 'Coulomb'
		},
		{
			question: '3) Chemical name of Vitamin B1?',
			answer: 'Thiamine'
		},
		{
			question: '4) Founder of Brahmo Samaj?',
			answer: 'Raja Ram Mohan Roy'
		},
		{
			question: '5) Full form of ATM?',
			answer: 'Automated Teller Machine'
		},
		{
			question: '6) Author of the book ‘Who will cry when you die’ is?',
			answer: 'Robin Sharma'
		},
		{
			question: '7) Each degree on a map is equal to ______ minutes?',
			answer: '60'
		},
		{
			question: '8) Formula for area of Equilateral Triangle?',
			answer: '√3/4 Side Square'
		},
		{
			question: '9) First Governor General of Independent India?',
			answer: 'C.Rajagopalachari'
		},
		{
			question: '10) Currency of Germany?',
			answer: 'Euro'
		},
		{
			question: '11) First fort captured by Chh. Shivaji Maharaj was?',
			answer: 'Torna Fort / Prachandgad'
		},
		{
			question: '12) Type of mirror used by E.N.T. specialist?',
			answer: 'Concave'
		},
		{
			question: '13) Current President of India?',
			answer: 'Ramnath Kovind'
		},
		{
			question: '14) ‘Wi-Fi’ is the combination of which 2 words?',
			answer: 'Wireless + Fidelity'
		},
		{
			question: '15) Winner of ‘Bharat Ratna’ in 2019?',
			answer: 'Bhupen Hazarika / Pranab Mukherjee / Nanaji Deshmukh'
		}
	],
	//For 4th choice
	[
		{
			question: '1) Instrument used to record the growth of plants is called?',
			answer: 'Crescograph'
		},
		{
			question: '2) A person who studies rocks is called?',
			answer: 'Geologist'
		},
		{
			question: '3) Earthworm respires through skin. True/False?',
			answer: 'True'
		},
		{
			question: '4) The Hornbill festival is celebrated in which state?',
			answer: 'Arunachal Pradesh'
		},
		{
			question: '5) Factors of (x^2- 169) are?',
			answer: '(x + 13) (x - 13)'
		},
		{
			question: '6) Author of the book ‘A century is  not enough’ is?',
			answer: 'Sourav Ganguly'
		},
		{
			question: '7) Father of India’s White Revolution is?',
			answer: 'Varghese Kurien'
		},
		{
			question: '8) Gas also known as ‘Marsh Gas’ is?',
			answer: 'Methane'
		},
		{
			question: '9) The piece that can jump over other pieces in chess is?',
			answer: 'Knight'
		},
		{
			question: '10) Capital of Bangladesh is?',
			answer: 'Dhaka'
		},
		{
			question: '11) International Court of Justice is located in?',
			answer: 'Hague, Netherlands'
		},
		{
			question: '12) Full form of HIV is?',
			answer: 'Human Immunodeficiency Virus'
		},
		{
			question: '13) Daulatabad fort located in which district?',
			answer: 'Aurangabad'
		},
		{
			question: '14) Present Chief Minister of Maharashtra is?',
			answer: 'Udhhav Thakarey'
		},
		{
			question: '15) The plural of radius is?',
			answer: 'Radii'
		}
	],
	//For 5th choice
	[
		{
			question: '1) The suffix in the word ‘Uncomfortable’ is?',
			answer: 'Able'
		},
		{
			question: '2) Vitamin D is a fat soluble or Water soluble vitamin?',
			answer: 'Fat Soluble'
		},
		{
			question: '3) The person who studies weather is called?',
			answer: 'Meteorologist'
		},
		{
			question:
				'4) If Selling price is more than the cost price, it is called Loss. True / False?',
			answer: 'False'
		},
		{
			question: '5) Full form of CNG is?',
			answer: 'Compressed Natural Gas'
		},
		{
			question: '6) The capital of Greece is?',
			answer: 'Athens'
		},
		{
			question: '7) The highest peak in India?',
			answer: 'Kanchenjunga'
		},
		{
			question: '8) The place where soldiers live is called?',
			answer: 'Barrack'
		},
		{
			question: '9) Guinea pig is a species of Pig. True or False? ',
			answer: 'False'
		},
		{
			question: '10) The author of the book ‘The race of my life’ is?',
			answer: 'Milkha Singh'
		},
		{
			question:
				'11) Sanctuary that preserves endangered species of the One Horned Rhino in India is?',
			answer: 'Kaziranga Wildlife Sanctuary'
		},
		{
			question: '12) Golden Girl of India is a nickname of?',
			answer: 'P.T.Usha'
		},
		{
			question: '13) Father of Genetics is?',
			answer: 'Gregor Mendel'
		},
		{
			question:
				'14) Marathi dramatic narration praising heroic deeds are called?',
			answer: 'Powada'
		},
		{
			question: '15) Surface area of sphere is?',
			answer: '4πr2'
		}
	],
	//For 6th choice
	[
		{
			question: '1) Acid mainly found in milk is?',
			answer: 'Lactic Acid'
		},
		{
			question: '2) Who designed the Indian flag?',
			answer: 'Pingalli Venkayya'
		},
		{
			question: '3) Olympic games originated in?',
			answer: 'Greece'
		},
		{
			question: '4) The mountain ranges known as ‘Abode of Snow’ are?',
			answer: 'Himalayas'
		},
		{
			question: '5) Capital of Sri Lanka is?',
			answer: 'Colombo'
		},
		{
			question:
				'6) If market value of share is greater than the face value, share is at ____ ?',
			answer: 'Premium'
		},
		{
			question: '7) Author of the book ‘India 2020’ is?',
			answer: 'Dr. A.P.J Abdul Kalam'
		},
		{
			question: '8) If GST on certain goods is 18%, what is the CGST?',
			answer: '9%'
		},
		{
			question: '9) Full form of PNR is _______.',
			answer: 'Passenger Name Record'
		},
		{
			question: '10) Study of Sound is called ______. ',
			answer: 'Acoustics'
		},
		{
			question: '11) Aga Khan Cup is related to which sport?',
			answer: 'Hockey'
		},
		{
			question: '12) Helpline number for Police Control Room India is?',
			answer: '100'
		},
		{
			question:
				'13) In 2019, Wing Commander Abhinandan was awarded with which award?',
			answer: 'Veer Chakra'
		},
		{
			question: '14) Prince of Wales Museum is now known as?',
			answer: ' Chhatrapati Shivaji Maharaj Vastu Sangrahalay '
		},
		{
			question: '15) Pongal festival is celebrated in which state?',
			answer: 'Tamil Nadu'
		}
	]
];
